Guide to the William R. Scott, Inc. Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
William R. Scott, Inc. records
1938-1997
1938-1960
YCAL MSS 447
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
7
(27 boxes) + 11 broadside folders
Contains original artwork, including drawings, color separations, and reproduction proofs, for children's books published by William R. Scott, Inc.
William R. Scott, Inc
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Virginia Scott Sterling and Ethel McCullough Scott, 1998 and 1999.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
William R. Scott, Inc.
William Rufus Scott, founder of the small publishing house William R. Scott, Inc., was born August 27, 1910. He graduated from Yale University in 1931 and worked for several small publishers, where he developed skill as a typographer and learned about illustrating. Scott founded William R. Scott, Inc. in 1938 with his wife, Ethel McCullough Scott, and her brother, John C. McCullough, and began to publish children's books. The first editor was Margaret Brown, who published ''The Noisy Book,'' in 1939. Around 1972, Scott sold his publishing house to Addison-Wesley and most of the books previously published went out of print. Years later, some were reissued by HarperCollins and by the Linnet imprint of Shoe String Press.
Scott is considered a pioneering publisher of modern children's books and created vibrant books with creative educational content. He died on July 22, 1997 in North Bennington, VT at the age of 86.
Scope and Contents
The William R. Scott, Inc. Records contains original artwork, including drawings, color separations, and reproduction proofs, for children's books published by William R. Scott, Inc.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by book title.
Children's literature -- Illustrations; Children's literature -- Publishing -- United States; Publishers and publishing -- United States; Scott, William R. (William Rufus), 1910-; William R. Scott, Inc
- William R. Scott, Inc. Records, 1938-1997
  - William R. Scott catalog of children's books, undated (Box 1)
  - "Celebrating Bill Scott," invitation for a celebration in honor of Scott by the Vermont Arts Exchange, 1997 October 4 (Box 1)
  - Anywhere in the World: The Story of Plant and Animal Adaptation, [1947] (Box 1)
  - Anywhere in the World: The Story of Plant and Animal Adaptation, [1947]; 2 (Box 2)
  - Anywhere in the World: The Story of Plant and Animal Adaptation, [1947] (Box 6)
  - All About Eggs and How They Change Into Animals, [1952] (Box 12 Oversize)
  - Animal Hide and Seek, [1947]; 2 (Box 12 Oversize)
  - Animal Hide and Seek, [1947] (Box 28 Broadside)
  - The Apple That Jack Ate, [1951] (Box 6)
  - At Our House, [1943] (Box 6)
  - Bad Trouble in Miss Alcorn's Class, [1959] (Box 12 Oversize)
  - Barbara's Birthday, [1946] (Box 13 Oversize)
  - Blue Guess Book, undated (Box 2)
  - Blue Guess Book, undated; 2 (Box 1)
  - Captain Joe and the Eskimo, [1943] (Box 13 Oversize)
  - Captain Joe and the Eskimo, [1943]; 2 (Box 7)
  - A Child's Good Morning, [1952] (Box 1)
  - A Child's Good Morning, [1952]; 2 (Box 2)
  - A Child's Good Night Book, [1950] (Box 3)
  - A Child's Good Night Book, [1950] (Box 13 Oversize)
  - Christmas Stocking, [1946] (Box 8)
  - The Comical Tragedy or Tragical Comedy Of Punch and Judy, [1940] (Box 8)
  - The Comical Tragedy or Tragical Comedy Of Punch and Judy, [1940] (Box 13 Oversize)
  - [ Cortez and the Conquest of the Spaniards in 1521 ], undated; 2 (Box 1)
  - [ Cortez and the Conquest of the Spaniards in 1521 ], undated; 3 (Box 3)
  - Country Noisy Book, [1938] (Box 1)
  - Country Noisy Book, [1938] (Box 3)
  - Dead Bird, undated (Box 3)
  - Everybody Eats, [1946]; 3 (Box 14 Oversize)
  - Everybody Eats, [1946] (Box 37 Broadside)
  - Everybody Has a House, undated (Box 1)
  - The Flower, [1955] (Box 14 Oversize)
  - Good Work: What Will You Be When You Grow Up?, [1948] (Box 8)
  - Good Work: What Will You Be When You Grow Up?, undated (Box 34 Broadside)
  - Guess What's in the Grass?, [1945]; 4 (Box 15 Oversize)
  - Guess What's in the Grass?, [1945] (Box 36 Broadside)
  - Heartbreak Hotel, undated (Box 1)
  - Heavy is a Hippopotamus, [1954] (Box 14 Oversize)
  - Here Comes Daddy, [1951] (Box 16 Oversize)
  - How Big is Big?, [1946]; 3 (Box 1)
  - How Big is Big?, undated; 3 (Box 17 Oversize)
  - How Big is Big?, [1946] (Box 38 Broadside)
  - How Many Kisses Good Night?, [1949] (Box 1)
  - How Many Kisses Good Night?, [1949] (Box 3)
  - How Your Body Works, undated (Box 4)
  - Hurry, Hurry: A Story of What Happened To a Hurrier, [1947] (Box 1)
  - Hurry, Hurry: A Story of What Happened To a Hurrier, [1947] (Box 8)
  - I Want To Fly, [1943] (Box 31 Broadside)
  - Is it Hard? Is it Easy?, [1960?] (Box 1)
  - It's About Time, [1955]; 2 (Box 18 Oversize)
  - Just Like You, undated (Box 8)
  - Keep Singing, Keep Humming: A Collection of Plays and Story Songs, [1946]; 2 (Box 14 Oversize)
  - Let's Look Under the City, [1950, 1954] (Box 1)
  - Let's Look Under the City, [1950, 1954]; 2 (Box 19 Oversize)
  - The Little Cowboy, [1947]; 2 (Box 1)
  - The Little Cowboy, [1947]; 3 (Box 20 Oversize)
  - The Little Fireman, [1938]; 3 (Box 21 Oversize)
  - The Little Fisherman, [1938] (Box 1)
  - Little Indian the Big Fish Pusher or How Little Indian Got His Name, undated (Box 1)
  - The Log of Christopher Columbus, [1938] (Box 35 Broadside)
  - The Man in the Manhole and the Fix-It Men, [1946]; 3 (Box 20 Oversize)
  - The Man in the Manhole and the Fixit Men, [1946] (Box 32 Broadside)
  - More Power to You, [1953]; 3 (Box 22 Oversize)
  - The Noisy Bird Book, [1943] (Box 4)
  - Noisy Book, [1939]; 2 (Box 1)
  - Now Try This, [1947]; 2 (Box 8)
  - The Red, White and Blue Auto, [1943] (Box 8)
  - The River Horse, [1953] (Box 8)
  - "A Rose is a Rose" broadside, undated (Box 23 Oversize)
  - Sancho and his Stubborn Mule, [1954]; 2 (Box 1)
  - Saturday Flight, [1954] (Box 1)
  - This Is the Bread That Betsy Ate, [1945]; 3 (Box 23 Oversize)
  - This Is the Bread That Betsy Ate, [1945]; 3 (Box 9)
  - This is the Milk That Jack Drank, [1944] (Box 4)
  - This is the Way the Animals Walk, [1946]; 2 (Box 4)
  - A Time for Sleep: How the Animals Rest, [1953] (Box 24 Oversize)
  - The Travels of Ching, [1943] (Box 1)
  - Two Little Trains, [1949] (Box 10)
  - Ups and Downs: A First Book About Space, [1951] (Box 10)
  - The Very Little Dog, [1949] (Box 10)
  - Watch the Birdie, [1947] (Box 10)
  - Watch the Birdie, [1947] (Box 5)
  - What Do They Say?, [1950]; 2 (Box 25 Oversize)
  - What Would You Do?, [1954] (Box 1)
  - What Would You Do?, [1954] (Box 11)
  - What's in a Line, [1951] (Box 26 Oversize)
  - When Will the World Be Mine?, undated; 2 (Box 4)
  - While Susie Sleeps, [1948] (Box 26 Oversize)
  - Who Blew That Whistle?, [1946]; 2 (Box 5)
  - Willie's Walk to Grandma's, [1944] (Box 1)
  - Willie's Walk to Grandma's, [1944] (Box 29 Broadside)
  - Unidentified, undated; 2 (Box 1)
  - Unidentified, undated; 4 (Box 5)
  - Unidentified, undated; 4 (Box 27 Oversize)
  - Unidentified (animals in farm and city), undated (Box 30 Broadside)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 33 Broadside)
  - Two unidenitified photographs, undated (Box 11)